Wahyu Setianto

Ciracas, East Jakarta, 13740 | 081314761132 | wahyusetianto19@gmail.com | github.com/Hyuto | hyuto.github.io

Data Enthusiast

I am a Data Enthusiast who has a deep interest in data field. I believe with decision made based on data can have more impact in solving problems in real world. I have a lot of experience in processing data to gain insight and solve problems with various method (such as *machine learning, deep learning, nlp, etc.*). I have deep knowledge on several data analysis tools such as Python and R. I am also interested in *web development* to create a website as a hobby.

Experience

PT TaniHub Indonesia

March 2022 – August 2022

Data Scientist Intern

Responsible for preparing and helping work on projects intended for the Data Science department. Such as customer segmentation projects using the RFM clustering process, sentiment analysis on competitors' social media comments, and price forecasting for several SKUs.

PT Ivonesia Solusi Data (Ivosights)

July 2021 – October 2021

Operation & Data

Preparing brand report projects by making analytical reports from several social media platforms within 6-month period using *descriptive statistics, data visualization, forecasting,* and *sentiment analysis* to gain insight from data.

Bangkit Academy by Google

February 2021 - July 2021

Machine Learning Student

Learning about materials that have been prepared in path of *machine learning* using Tensorflow. Responsible for completing the final project to build an application using *mobile, cloud,* and *machine learning* technology.

Education

State University of Jakarta

2018 - 2023

Statistics

• GPA: 3.61 /4.00

BIDIKMISI scholarship (2018 – 2022)

58 Jakarta High School

2015 - 2018

Mathematics and Science

Technical Skill Set

| Programming Language | Skills | | Operating Systems | | Other Tech | |
|--------------------------------|--------|--|----------------------|-------------------|------------|----------------------|
| Python | | Machine Learning (Supervised & Unsupervised) | • | Windows | • | VSCode |
| • R | • | Deep Learning (Tensorflow) | • | Linux (Ubuntu) | • | Rstudio Ms. Excel |
| • SQL | • | Forecasting | | | | |
| Javascript | • | Data Visualization | | | | |
| Typescript | | | | | | |

Achievement

Finalist | Group October 2021

Big Data Competition – Satria Data 2021 (National)

Puspresnas & IPB University

Classifying gender and detecting a person's age based on image data.

2nd place & Best Metric Performance | Group

October 2020

Lomba Big Data Competition – Satria Data 2020 (National)

Puspresnas & IPB University

Classifying hoaxes based on image data and text data from news.

Organization

BPRS ERAFM UNJ March 2020 – January 2021

Creative Design

Certification

TensorFlow: Data and Deployment Specialization May 2021

Coursera

DeepLearning.Al TensorFlow Developer Specialization April 2021

Coursera

Google IT Automation with Python Specialization March 2021

Coursera

Certificate of Stargazer June 2020

CodeAbbey

Microsoft Professional Program in Data Science

January 2019

Digital Talent Scholarship

Projects

Serving Machine Learning Models Live in The Browser

March 2023

Build simple web applications that load machine learning models directly in them without the help of a server. Uses several web technologies such as Tensorflow.js, onnxruntime-web, and pyodide to carry pre-trained machine learning models. These projects include:

- Object Detection and Object Segmentation with YOLO
- Deploying Scikit-Learn models in the web with ONNX

Emotional Analysis of Public Opinion About the Covid-19 Vaccine

On Social Media Twitter Using Support Vector Machine

September 2022

Create a model to classify public opinion using OCEAN analysis on several social media platform related to the topic of "PPKM" in Indonesia.

Gender & Age Detection | Group

November 2021

Create a model with the aim of classifying gender and detecting a person's age from image data. This project was carried out to solve the challenges of Big Data Competition – Satria Data 2021

RangRang | Group June 2021

Mobile application that aims to teach children to identify objects around them in English. RangRang is an application that combines 3 elements, namely mobile development, cloud computing, and machine learning. This project was carried out as the final project of Bangkit 2021.

Hoax Classification | Group

November 2020

Create a model with the aim of classifying Hoax based on the text and image data. This project was carried out to solve the challenges of the Big Data Competition – Satria Data 2020.

Analysis of DKI Jakarta's Corona Twitter Sentiment

April 2020

Create a model to classify public opinion that is poured out on Twitter social media related to the topic of "corona" in the DKI Jakarta area and its surroundings.